[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
"In truth, I was embarrassed.
Every burning touch of your hand
upon my body
caused a stirring and rising heat,
and my body twisted.
And I was…
embarrassed quite abundantly.
It was also painful
once you were fully inside of me…
as if my flesh were being flayed,
and it left me in a daze.
However…
Ah, the instant
I felt your skin moving inside of me,
I realized, once and for all.
And let me say,
however many nights I have left,
I wish to share with you
and to stay with you
until my days run out.
Pray, stay beside me
as you are beside me now."
That woman is such a sorry simpleton.
She's as amusing as she is pathetic.
Now, cousin, won't you tell me
how you experienced that?
Tell me, was there
a stirring in your bones
as the young widow lay down?
The lady never had a man,
at least not really.
She latched on to my neck…
then she begged me with her eyes.
How warm and tender that was.
Oh, was it, pray tell?
I take it you're displeased.
And if I am, so what?
You know as well as I, dear cousin,
why I went to such lengths.
Everything is because of you.
Now, then…
Will this finally be the day?
For so long, I've been expecting that.
Yet, we'll have to delay this…
bestowing of your reward.
I was enjoined to see
a matter of great tenor.
What on earth…
Oh, my God.
I hear you were directed to retrieve
the remains of the young widow.
Still, I knew you'd be thinking
of that wretched wager.
So, I thought I'd write it on your behalf.
But I did not realize
how very desperately the young widow
has come to cling to this life.
She has forgotten
all about her promises, I guess.
What are you saying?
I wrote a marriage proposal letter.
And certain promises have been made.
Notably that she will, at the very least,
fulfill her duty
and let death carry her off.
It is fitting and apt, is it not?
That's how it is. Her life ends now.
It is regrettable to learn
that she is still alive,
though it won't matter much, I guess.
For, as we know,
death will occur in the end.
All you need to do, dear cousin,
is take what I have written
and present it to His Majesty.
Go to him with these words,
that some are saying
that they saw an abominable thing.
A woman who threw herself off a cliff.
Are you telling me
that I should tell a despicable lie?
When the young widow hears
what everyone says happened,
she will know that the only option
she has is to end it all.
And, gladly, she will do so.
Then, all shall be restored
to its rightful place.
Your concern for me
may be heavenly in aspect…
…however, this kindness, dear cousin,
is far too much.
This thing
shouldn't really involve you at all.
Really? Do you think so?
Dear cousin,
can you recall the day that you…
took my verse, which I wrote for you,
and brought the family honor?
As I did then, I am merely trying
to come to your assistance.
I'll never forget it,
of that you can be sure.
Yes, I remember well
that piercing gaze you fixed on me.
If it were possible, cousin…
If I could go back in time,
I would say I did not write those lines,
that you wrote it all,
right from the beginning.
And I…
I am no longer the child I had been.
-Won…
-Do not call me that.
You say you wrote that to help me,
as you were helping me then?
Then so be it.
Very well.
In that case, I ask, as I did then,
to hold my hand once more.
And this time you will come along.
I'm glad…
at last I heard you speak these words.
I've waited so long for you
to ask that I follow you again.
I couldn't stop thinking about it,
since the day that I could not go to you…
About the ferry boat I had to watch
through my tears drift away.
And I've wondered
if I might see that ferry once again.
So please, do tell me more.
Tell me of the future you envision for us.
Even now, I would enjoy
hearing you speak of that.
And of Yanjing,
where they say that wonders
of every sort are gathered.
Hmm?
Cho Won…
Cho Won.
I wished to call you by your name.
Hui-yeon.
Mmm.
My lady…
The Young Master In-ho was here.
He was outside the gate a minute ago.
He was watching me there.
My lord, where we go doesn't matter to me.
You must come away with me,
that's what matters.
Won't you come away with me, please?
It's going to be fine.
My heart is filled with joy
now that you've told me that.
Improper as it might be, yes.
All right.
Where shall we go now?
Across the sea?
I think not.
What if we went to Yanjing?
No one will ever find us.
Mm-hmm.
How I've waited for you
to ask me to leave with you again.
It doesn't matter where.
How about Yanjing, where they say
that wonders of every sort are gathered?
Hmm?
How long I've been waiting…
waiting to hear you say that.
Tell me more now, won't you?
About…
our future together.
There is one more thing you must hear.
His Majesty has given me a command
to retrieve the remains
of the Left State Councilor's
daughter-in-law,
now that she has bid farewell
and passed away.
Whatever it takes,
I'll manage to find a way, so I think… I…
You, my lady, should go on ahead.
No, I refuse.
Did you not say you wanted to live?
Yes, I have made it very clear…
that I want to be living with you,
my lord.
That cannot be.
Hyah! Hyah!
The truth is,
I have come to ask you a favor.
I need to find someone
a position right away.
Who's that?
-A woman.
-A… A woman?
A woman in disguise.
Huh. Oh-Oh…
Young master, please rise.
I have brought some porridge for you.
I have a terrible headache.
Oh, a headache?
In-ho… Oh, goodness.
What on earth has befallen you?
Oh.
I told you I don't wish to eat.
Why do you…
Shh.
I didn't know your manners
were so inappropriate.
You could've let me know a little sooner.
You're in no position
to laugh at me right now.
The girl, my brother-in-law's concubine…
…has asked me to deliver this to you.
No one ever informed me
that you are a man who lusts after women.
I could've done something.
I could have thoroughly warned
my cousin about you.
I wonder what His Excellency
will have to say.
What…
Master, I'm…
Hey, wait.
What is it, young master?
Why are you acting like that?
Don't worry too much.
I'm not going to speak of this to anybody.
As a scholar-official, one's duty
is to protect the honor of the family.
However, there are…
delicate matters which,
once uncovered, can't be handled.
You said you're no longer
the child that you once were.
But, as for me,
to come away with you once again,
dear cousin,
it was like I was
reunited with the compassionate man
I knew when I was young.
My whole body shook with impatience.
So, Hwaseong. I heard you went there
in order to have done
with the quandary of the young widow?
Yes.
And if, in the end,
we circled back to where it all began,
then I would say
that silly wager was unnecessary.
Tell me, the young widow,
what happened in the end?
Did she go away without any ado?
Her strength seemed gone,
as was any lingering attachment.
She will die by her own hand.
It'll happen soon.
I think that's true.
I am relieved in a way, I guess.
One obstacle has arisen.
Though I know not how,
the Left State Councilor's son…
learned about this entire matter.
We can trust the young master, I'd say.
He is of a tender disposition,
and I'm sure
he won't be speaking out of turn.
What is more distressing
is that this matter has been told
to the Lady of the First Rank.
I should've told you right away,
but I feared
I might cause you needless worry.
She has made it plain she could ignore
the troubles that we're talking about
so long as approval for the Memorial Gate
for Virtuous Women is forthcoming.
She asked me
to ensure the project goes through.
Have you been blackmailed?
It was a request to be of help in this.
-Oh, cousin.
-Go to His Majesty
and say the words exactly
as I have written them down.
I pray that is all you need to do.
Then no one and nothing will trouble you
or trouble me with this ever again,
dear cousin.
All right.
I held on to this
to show you when you returned.
Here it is.
Isn't that you, my lord?
THERE WAS A MAN
WHO WENT ABOUT SCOLDING
MOIST WOMANHOODS
WITH HIS LARGE HANDS
And…
Where did you get this?
Eun-sil's mistress wanted it burned,
but the women of the house
were all passing it around.
Eun-sil thought perhaps you should see it,
so she traded for it.
Cost her some dried beef too.
-Bun-hui…
-Bun-hui?
-Bun-hui.
Go to Mapo Ferry Crossing. I need a favor.
-Hmm.
-I shall leave for Yanjing.
Yanjing? The Great State?
Whether by ship or by road,
find the swiftest and most discreet route.
One other thing…
It should be comfortable enough
for a woman to travel it.
Ah, a woman?
-Who else could catch your eye so…
-What about Eun-sil?
You'll leave her behind?
Eun-sil?
Eun… Eun-sil is coming with us to Yanjing?
Truly?
I have to be somewhere.
Do a good job with that.
I will.
Dear cousin…
I see you're going somewhere.
I'm making arrangements for us
to leave together, am I not?
Oh, but…
Then when will you go to see His Majesty?
It will not be long.
If you fasten this so loosely,
it will soon come undone.
Tighten it around you like so.
There you are.
Be careful on the road.
I shall.
Hmm.
Hyah!
Oh, young master!
What's the matter?
I only went out for a moment,
and when I came back, she was gone.
I humbly apologize, young master.
That's all right.
I'm the one who did this.
Oh, dear.
Tell me then,
when will your mother be arriving?
That is… I don't think
she will be able to come today.
Uh… She's gone to Mapo Ferry Crossing
to get tobacco from Qing.
And she always likes
to verify it all herself.
So, I don't think she'll be back
until sunset, madam.
-Is that so?
-Yes, madam.
I have entrusted
a certain matter to your mother,
but I've had no word from her
in quite some time,
so I've come in person.
Perhaps if I had been more kind
in my instructions,
she would have responded
with greater urgency.
I am not fond of repeating myself,
much less several times…
so this I shall not say a third time.
I shall give you a fortnight.
Do make sure they're all gone.
I have worked too hard
to preserve my honor and reputation
to let gossip tarnish them in this way.
I'll count on you to tell her.
Yes, madam.
How could she do this to me, hmm?
When So-ok's belly begins to swell,
she'll be relegated to the back room.
The gall. How could she do this to me?
Oh, Mother, is there anything wrong?
What do you think? Huh?
I'm so angry I could die!
Yet, I would say…
Um… When you're angry like this,
you're so beautiful.
Fool!
You have no sense of decorum, do you?
Confound it.
I am so angry.
I am very angry.
Uh, excuse me.
This is a counterfeit drawing.
What difference could that make
for erotic paintings?
If they're provocative,
that's all that counts.
All the erotic paintings
that you've gathered so far
are merely serviceable copies,
and they're spreading all over Hanyang.
It isn't just one or two.
There must be dozens of them.
In fact, by now there must be
hundreds of them.
You won't be finished anytime soon.
Before his lord arrives,
see to it that the servants…
Madam?
Gye-hwa…
Yes, madam?
Send So-ok and the servants
out of the house.
And bolt the gate as quick as you can.
Uh. Yes. Right away, madam.
-What's going on?
-Does anyone know what this is about?
Has my cousin arrived yet?
No, he has not arrived yet.
When he gets here, tell me at once.
Yes, ma'am.
Let's hurry.
Your courage is quite remarkable.
Mocking your sworn agreement
to pass on with honor…
What possessed you to come back here?
My shame is mine alone.
Let's hear your explanation.
Why are you here now?
Why did you choose to see me like this?
Please persuade my lord.
What are you attempting to say?
My lord
has been given an order
to find and retrieve my lifeless remains.
He told me to go away first,
that he would find some way
to find me later.
You're saying that my cousin
said all of that to you?
He made me swear to him
that I would go ahead…
go until I found a secure place to hide.
But I fear if my lord lies
to the king because of me,
his life will be in peril.
I cannot go forward alone
and leave my lord behind.
If you are so worried
about the life of my dear cousin…
could you not save him
by eliminating the lie all together?
Whoa.
Ah, my lord.
Is something the matter?
Well, now…
My cousin shows romantic affections,
and suddenly you are afraid to die?
Now your chastity and the honor
of your family mean nothing to you?
Do all your principles no longer matter?
Oh, my lady.
If your affection is truly deep enough
to save one who is condemned,
why did you not intervene
in a more intimate way?
You brought your trouble
instead into this house.
Tell me why I should aid in such behavior.
Weak, cowardly woman.
Hmm.
Mm-hmm.
I am weak.
However, the only place that came to mind
was here with you.
Madam, did you not…
make me a confidant with your secret?
Did we not form a friendship together?
You're bringing up my secret…
Is that true friendship?
I beg of you, my lady.
I ask that you simply persuade my lord.
He must not speak to His Majesty.
My lady!
Lord Cho Won…
Exactly why have you come here?
To appeal for the aid of my lady.
I cannot go on my own
and leave you behind.
I beg of you, madam.
Please, you must tell him.
Tell him he must not go to His Majesty.
Tell him to come away with me.
Since you are earnest,
I shall do your bidding.
I shall assist both of you
to go away together.
For I am not
without a compassionate heart.
However…
Dear cousin, I wish to hear these words
from your own mouth.
Tell me your intentions.
Tell me truly.
Will you be leaving,
you and this woman, together?
I pray that we will leave
this place together.
I…
Will I have the strength to leave?
My lord.
I fought to avoid it…
though I won't escape
what has appeared in my heart.
I could no sooner do the same
after you left, my lord.
That is pure affection.
Yes.
There is someone that is dear to me.
Is this a dream?
It would be so simple
for you to leave with me.
It was of me
that you were speaking, right?
Have you decided which path to take?
Will you choose
to change his lies into the truth
in order to save my dear cousin
from danger?
Or will you choose to leave here
and live your life quietly,
as though you were dead?
Would it please you if I could devise
a way for you to live in solitude?
You would need to choose.
My lord?
Tell me now.
Was your affection real?
Real?
Let's say, when she was begging like that,
for me to leave with her…
you could say that
what I was feeling was real.
Now, cousin…
I was pained to see her cling to me
as I desperately clung to you.
And yet,
that is precisely when it became clear…
that you, cousin…
never meant to run off with me at all.
I could not take her away with me,
and so I fabricated some dreams
and ramblings.
"Shall we cross the sea or go to Yanjing?"
I came to know how it is for you.
From the start, you knew that
leaving with me was an impossible thing.
I trembled at that.
At the thought of being abandoned.
What irony.
Dear cousin, you must know…
the bond between us can never be severed.
Why can you not comprehend it?
As promised,
you have reported the matter
of the young widow and…
I pray…
Please return to me, my dear cousin.
I wish to know each and every detail
and everything you can read
in His Majesty's face
when he replies
to the words I've put down.
Pray…
You will report back to me, will you not?
As you wish, dear cousin.
You can count on me.
Tell me why you chose to approach me…
when obviously another woman
is the object of your affections?
Your chastity was the object
of a wager we made.
I couldn't hold your body
and your heart in my hand.
It was my chance to win the heart
of the one I yearned for my whole life.
It was a… a wager
I could not sensibly refuse.
My virtue and honor are now gone…
because you wanted
to possess another woman then?
That is the truth, yes.
You are depraved.
Are her virtues now corrupted as well?
They're not.
Why is that?
If you chose to cause me so much shame…
why would you not have taken hers?
The Left State Councilor's house
is nearby.
I fear that someone will spot you here.
I will no more ask you of any great favor.
But please don't die.
Live on and live well.
I fear I hold deep resentment
towards you, my lord.
However, mortality is my claim.
Despite the rage
that now dwells in my heart.
Cheong, come in here now.
If you please,
I feel a need to dress beautifully.
Your mastery of the written language
is indeed surprising.
I see you were unable
to retrieve the body.
But with the help of your words,
the tragic image
of her dignified death is very clear.
That said, the Left State Councilor
must be informed as well.
Tell me more about the witness.
A papermaker witnessed it.
He saw the instant of her death.
He is the supplier
for the Hwaseong construction.
According to his recollections…
it was in the morning.
The hour was very early.
There was water gushing,
because of the heavy rain,
toward the cliff.
He filled his bucket,
and when he looked up,
he saw a noblewoman weeping
in bitter sorrow.
But then, in the blink of an eye,
she went over the cliff
and plummeted to the river below.
The river was flooded,
so no one could find the lady's remains.
That coincides with the day
the daughter-in-law's brother
began dispatching people to find her.
That very day.
It had to be the daughter-in-law
who jumped in.
Your Majesty, I am afraid…
…it was my oversight
that caused this pain.
I humbly beg you
not to approve the Memorial Gate.
That is not right.
Is there among us a man
with the power to stop the heavy rain?
Hear my words, Left State Councilor.
Approval has been granted
for the Memorial Gate.
You must accept this.
Your Majesty, I am utterly overwhelmed
by your boundless grace.
I am utterly overwhelmed.
I merely obeyed the command
that was given to me.
Cho Won, come over here.
Follow me.
I consider this construction work to be
the most important undertaking of my life.
Therefore, since my body
is confined to the palace,
I depend on the confidential accounts
of many officials
concerning conditions and circumstances
throughout Hwaseong daily.
On the day prior to when the deceased
threw herself into the river…
a light shower fell briefly in Hwaseong,
correct?
Well, speak. I'm listening.
Thinking I could be misled
with such paltry poppycock…
Why would you even try?
Is there something that you can't say?
Or someone you would protect,
even if it costs you your life?
You are just as you have always been.
You wag your tongue
with no thought of consequences.
However…
I have always envied that about you too.
In all my life, I have never
drawn a breath as my own person.
Always living in the shadow
of the late king, as someone's son.
Yes, I envy you, for you live untethered,
flying free.
That is why I have prized you so dearly.
That's why I kept you close,
though you were hardly ready,
and watched you act in my stead.
I hoped you could be my trusted confidant.
Your Highness…
I humbly beg you to hear what I say.
To tell you the truth…
I'm like a bird locked up in a cage.
Never once have I taken flight.
Cho Won, hear what I say.
For daring to offend
and insult the sovereign,
our friendship is ended forthwith.
Never again
shall you be granted an audience with me.
His Majesty was greatly moved
by the words you wrote, dear cousin.
You described that death so vividly
that His Majesty seemed more affected
by the sorrow of losing one of his people
than by the gravity of the Memorial Gate.
Thus, the Memorial Gate for Virtuous Women
shall be bestowed upon
the Left State Councilor's family.
What trouble you've taken
to carry so precious a letter.
Thank you, madam.
Gye-hwa, are you outside?
Please prepare some drinks…
-Yes, madam.
-…for when my cousin arrives.
No. That's all right.
I think I'll go and wait outside.
You arrive just in time.
Though I…
Are you going to be alone?
I was told there was a lady,
so I came to escort her.
Well, this is how it turned out.
Now then…
I shall pay you the same fare,
so let's go now.
Very well.
All right then, here we go.
All right. Let us depart.
What business do you have in Yanjing?
It doesn't look to me
like you are going there to study.
You do have a sharp eye.
You're not going off to live in hiding
after committing some great offense,
are you?
That would put me in some jeopardy.
A life of chasing women…
Now two of them are chasing me.
How vile is that?
So now I'm making a…
…a run for it in the dead of night.
Oh. Only two, you say?
I wouldn't mind three.
Even four would be no problem!
Uh, you just say the word,
and I'll turn the boat around.
It doesn't seem that you particularly
wish to run away, that's for sure.
If I turn around now,
I'll only charge you half the fare, okay?
Who do I have to go back to anyway?
My lord?
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, goodness! My lord!
My lord!
My lord! My lord!
Blast it! Good heavens!
Do you know how hard it is
to be born a nobleman?
Damn it.
Oh, for goodness' sakes!
Keep the pace now!
Let's go, let's go. No slowing down!
Mister, I'm off to make deliveries
to Hanyang.
-All right.
-I'm going along with him.
I packed some snacks.
Yes, go.
But keep your eyes open.
Who can say?
Lord Cho Won could still be in the area.
What use is it to meet
a heartless noble like him?
Are you an idiot, man?
He freed you, didn't he?
He paid to have Eun-sil released.
Even asked me to see to it
you could make a living.
And that's all you have to say?
Come on.
I was upset. That's all.
I don't know if he's dead or alive.
And if he's alive,
he could've sent word to me.
Off with you. Do your errands. Hurry back.
We're leaving.
This paper is always good quality.
Thank you very much.
I was careful to choose
the best of the best, of course.
I am very glad it brought you delight.
Is your work going well then?
Not too difficult, I hope?
Oh, dear.
To live as a proper human isn't difficult.
I only wish that my lord…
May I… May I be on my way now?
I will deliver this, of course…
But why do you keep writing them
when there's no reply?
Would you kindly take it?
I heard there's a new sister
who's joining us today.
We've recently had many new sisters,
much more than usual.
And a welcome thing that is indeed.
She should be here by now.
-She's here. Mmm.
-Oh.
Here. Go on.
Welcome.
I'm very sorry. It's my first time,
and I guess I was a little late.
Everybody is here. We can begin.
A vow, when made before God,
ought to be in accordance
with what is true and just.
I was told we needed more candles
for our new arrivals.
-Ah. Hmm.
-…then this is an insult to God,
and a mockery of his grace.
Therefore, we must always be sincere.
Why, of course.
You can't expect to live well,
if you live a life of lies, can you?
That is true.
I am correct. Am I not correct?
-Mmm.
-Yes.
Let us continue.
Even if you refrain
from invoking the holy name of God,
the sin is the same as if you did
call upon that holy name of God.
Heaven, earth, and all things
were indeed created by God for humankind.
Why?
Why aren't you going inside?
Are you just going to leave?
Mmm.
I have some business
to attend to right away.
I'm making this humble request.
…and therefore, the Mother of God
has designated one special day
out of every seven days.
And this is called the Lord's Day.
Amen.
Ever on goes time
Flowers all bloom
Bees and butterflies
Oh, young master!
Come flying
-It is nature's way
-Oh!
That doesn't mean
it always aligns with the moral order.
That's nonsense!
What do you mean
the natural order isn't the moral order?
As the saying goes!
What you've planted here
Will be what you'll reap
It's obvious
A three-year-old child would know that
If you said a noble woman
Would throw her pillow
I swear… I would believe that
More than what you're saying
-That crying doesn't sound ordinary
-How could they do this? How could they?
-I can't take it!
-Oh! Oh, dear.
Oh! Oh, my. Look, look, look, look.
It seems she is still full of life.
Even Buddha himself
couldn't overcome boiling rage.
Indeed. Blessed are those who endure.
Hear the temple's moktak,
tak, tak, tak, tak…
Neighboring red-bean
Fell into a field of beans
And so it happened, it got mixed in
Entwined and entangled all together
Bukchon's noble gentry all pretend
They don't notice it
As they're all drunk
On liquor and power
Isn't it such a joy
To practice and to learn?
Come this way! This way!
Hmm…Then you might as well
Raise one leg, good grief!
I don't know what you're learning
Or what you're practicing
However, it is still such a big joy
Even butterflies
Sipping from white flowers
Go back to where they came from
Once their lives have run their course
And still we see springtime
Coming once more
But then… why hasn't it sprouted?
Black beans, chickpeas, speckled beans
What about kidney beans?
Soybeans
Beans, beans, beans, beans!
What kind of bean did you plant
that it won't sprout?
What do you mean, what kind of bean?
Well, one that was sitting for years
All dried up
And with no germ inside
It's that bean that I planted,
and you know what happened?
Well, it did actually sprout.
It wasn't supposed to sprout,
but somehow it did?
Doesn't it mean
everything turned out perfectly?
Didn't you watch Episode 1?
Stop saying nonsense
and go watch it again.
Don't you see?
This sprout is actually
not that kind of sprout.
If that sprout isn't that kind of sprout,
then that sprout shows no promise at all.
It's a matter of principle.
The natural order can't be helped.
Then at least follow the right way.
This way, that way This way, that way
-What's that supposed to mean?
-What do you mean?
It means a dog ran off that way.
Oh, boy.
Speak of the devil. Here she comes.
She'll never be a lady.
Honestly, she has no shame.
Look, look, look, look, look.
No, but really look at her.
How can she show her face?
Come now. A mother-in-law
always loves her son-in-law.
True.
Green belongs with green
Crayfish sides with crab
Blood is thicker than water
Birds of a feather flock together
Each with their own
They all look so dignified
Yet they are nobles in name
And nothing more
It may not even be A bean seed
Maybe it is a red bean seed…
Her looks will not betray her
When she is burning with anger inside
They worked so hard
To keep it all secret, but still…
Listen, and you'll hear whispers
Hearsay, chitchat, rumor, and gossip
It's everywhere
Everywhere
Thanks to the tireless tongues
Of the ladies of Bukchon, all the time
Everyone who should know already knows
Everyone except Lord Yoo
He must not know
For if he did
Then he would never act this way
No one would ever act like that
Goodness, my friend
Still this? Even now?
See all the noblemen
Of Bukchon know it all
But just pretend they don't
My word…
I'm really sure even master performers
Would envy today's gathering
I admit, I'm so intimidated
I've nearly lost my voice
-Now it's time for me to go
-He thinks he's funny.
Next stop
Namchon's where I'm heading to
Really, my legs are trembling, you know
It's my escape, a chance to go
Yes, now go!
Why trouble yourself?
You have come all this way
when it's so cold.
I suppose, if someone
is still sending him letters…
it suggests that I'm not the only one
who can't believe that he is truly gone.
For so many years, I've been living
in the company of the young master.
So…
If I may be bold,
I can maybe read his mind a little.
"Go fetch her a little warm tea."
That's what he would say.
Please, go inside.
Cousin!
Dear cousin!
I have been doing well.
I am living as I always have.
Those moments
when I suddenly find myself wondering
if you have truly left
have grown more frequent.
And every time,
I think to myself…
If only I had followed you, dear cousin,
leaving nothing behind,
perhaps…
I would not have wound up with nothing
but this longing.
Dear cousin,
if, by any chance…
you are out there, still alive,
and only pretending to be dead,
then could you not return to me?
I am dying here,
even as I pretend to be alive.